Guide to the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Theodore Brise, Apr 18, 1980 (Cd Access OH-02-199, Cd 1, Cd Brise 1, Cassette 31, Cd ohaloh020178p1 / ohaloh020178p2, Box 1)
  Anarchism and Arbeter Ring, Los Angeles; Yiddish anarchist activists and the Rudolf Rocker Circle.
- Brookwood Labor College Description: Narration by Jon Bloom of slide show on history of Brookwood Labor College and Workers' Education Local 189, with comments by former Brookwood staff and students., Oct 10, 1982 (Cassette 32A-D)
- Niki Brorsen, May 20, 1975 (Cd Access OH-02-200, OH-02-201, Box 1, Cd Brorsen 1-2, Cassette 33, Cassette 33 A-B, Cd ohaloh020179b1p1 / ohaloh020179b1p2, Cd ohaloh020180b1p3 / ohaloh020180b1p4)
  Family background and growing up in San Francisco and Chicago, 1950s-60s; anti-war work and decision to join Young Socialist Alliance, late 1960s; work as a waitress and activities in restaurant union, 1970s.
- Peter Burch Description: Socialist Zionism, Socialist Workers Party and Young Socialist Alliance, Robert Williams case; c. 1950s-60s., Aug 24, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
  Transcript available, box 1
- David Burbank, Oct 6, 1984 (Cd Access OH-02-202, Box 1, Cd Burbank 1, Cassette 35, Cd ohaloh020181p1 / ohaloh020181p2)
  St Louis radicalism, 1930s; Socialist Party, American Workers Party, Trotskyist movement, Workers Party; CLR James in Missouri; gas workers1 unionization.
- Ann Burlak Description: Rhode Island Labor activities, communism, early 1930s., 1977 (Cassette 35.1, Cd Access OH-02-203, OH-02-204, OH-02-205, Cd OH-02-206, OH-02-207, Cd ohaloh020182b1p1 / ohaloh020182b1p2 / ohaloh020183b1p3 / ohaloh020183b1p4, Cd ohaloh020184b1p5 / ohaloh020184b1p6 /ohaloh020185b1p7 / ohaloh020185b1p8, Cd ohaloh020186b1p9 / ohaloh020186b1p10)
  no access cassettes / masters only
- Ann Burlak, undated (Cassette 36, Cd ohaloh020187p1, Cd Access OH-02-208)
- Fanny & Herman Cantor, Jan 11, 1979 (Cassette 37, Cd ohaloh020188p1 / ohaloh020188p2, Cd OH-02-209, Box 1, Cd Cantor 1)
  Immigration to US from Russia and development of social consciousness; growing up in New York's Hell's Kitchen; radicalism and cooperativism, 1920s-30s; reflections on current issues and younger radicals.
  Interview by Milton Cantor.
- Philip Caplowitz, Nov 15, 1980 (Cd Access OH-02-210, Cassette 38, Cd ohaloh020189b1p1 / ohaloh020189b1p2, Cd ohaloh020190b1p3, Box 1, Cassette 38 A-B, Cd Caplowitz 1-2)
  Immigration; activities of Jewish Communists in unions, 1920s-30s; Yiddish Culture and Yiddishe Kultur Farband, 1930s-1980s.
- Wendell Carroll Description: American Youth for Democracy; Independent Socialist League; ISL positions on Korean War, Rosenberg case, c. 1940s-1950s., Nov 30, 1983 (Cassette 39A-B)
  Transcript available
- Pincus Caruso Description: Origins of Labor (Poale) Zionism in Eastern Europe; Yiddishe Kempfer; Israel; c. 1930s-1940s., Mar 16, 1983 (Cassette 40A-B)
- Catholic Worker Conference >Description: Program to honor Dorothy Day and founding of the Catholic Worker; panel comments by John Cort and others. Trinity College, Worcester, Massachusetts., May 2, 1983 (Cassette 41A-B)
- Rev. Don Chase Description: US intervention in Nicaragua, 1928; Christian Socialism in San Francisco, 1930s-50s; Liberation Theology, 1970s-80s., Nov 5, 1983 (Cassette 44A-B)
- Bernard Chazanow, 1978 (Cd Access OH-02-097, Box 1, Cd Chazanow 1, Cd ohaloh0200091p1 / ohaloh0200091p2, Cassette 42)
  Narrative translation of part of his 1956 Yiddish autobiography, Days and Years.
- Bernard Chazanow, May 31, 1978 (Box 1, Cd Chazanow 2-4, Cassette 43, Cd ohaloh020191b1p1 / ohaloh020191b1p2, Cd ohaloh020192b1p3 / ohaloh020192b1p4, Cd ohaloh020193b1p5 / ohaloh020193b1p6, Cd OH-02-212, OH-02-213, OH-02-214, Cassette 43 A-C)
  ILGWU, 1909-1928; Political activist in Russia, 1898-1909.
- Rose Chernin, Oct 25, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Chernin 1, Cassette 45, Cd Access OH-02-018, Cd ohaloh020018p1 / ohaloh020018p2)
  Origins and activities of Los Angeles branch. Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born, 1940s-1950s; family life, problems and differences with daughter.
- Harold Christoffel Description: speaking of former president of United Auto Workers Local 248 (Allis Chalmers), 1930s., Jun 27, 1974 (Item Transcript only)
- Helen Ciminelli; Joe Richter; Ann David Description: SNPJ (Slovenian Benefit Society) and Henry Wallace, 1930s - 1970s, Oct 6, 1983 (Cassette 47)
  tape#: 1 U2E
- Alice Citron, Jan 6, 1981 (Cd ohaloh020019p1 / ohaloh020019p2, Cd Access OH-02-019, Cassette 48, Box 1, Cd Citron 1)
  Harlem teacher, 1930s-1940s; Teachers's Union; her dismissal during McCarthy era and struggle for reinstatement.
- CCNY Memorial Description: Recording of Dedication of memorial for 13 CCNY alumni members of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade killed in action in the Spanish Civil War., Apr 13, 1980 (Cassette 46A-B)
- Edigio Clemente, May 11, 1981 (Cd ohaloh020020p1 / ohaloh020020p2, Box 1, Cassette 50, Cd Access OH-02-020, Cd Clemente 1)
  Editor of La Parole, and secretary of Italian Socialist Federation, 1930s.
- Lucy Ann Cloud Description: Industrial Workers of the World, Centralia, Wash. reference to Elmer Smith, IWW attorney., Aug 25, 1972 (Item Transcript only)
- Charles Coe, Jan 1, 1992 (Cassette 315A-B)
  No access cassettes available / masters only
- Nat Cohen, Nov 5, 1979 (Cassette 392)
- Rose Cohen Description: Jefferson School of Social Science., Apr 12, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Joseph & Ruth Cohen Description: On "Carlo" (Jesse Cohen), cartoonist of the Workers Party, 1940s., Jun 9, 1983 (Cassette 51A-B)
- Julia Conroy, May 14, 1980 (Cd Access OH-02-215, Box 1, Cassette 53, Cd Conroy 1, Cd ohaloh020194p1 / ohaloh020194p2)
- Olga Corey, Jan 18, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020195p1 / ohaloh020195p2, Cassette 54, Box 1, Cd Access OH-02-216, Cd Corey 1)
  Experiences of Louis Fraina/Lewis Corey's daughter; reaction to the movie Reds; reminiscences of father at Antioch College, 1940s; her own union activities.
- Carlos Cortez, Jul 25, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020196b1p1 / ohaloh020196b1p2, Cd ohaloh020197b1p3 / ohaloh020197b1p4, Cassette 55, Box 1, Cassette 55 A-B, Cd Access OH-02-217, OH-02-218)
  Son of Mexican-American activist who joined Industrial Workers of the World after San Diego Free Speech Fight; father's life in Milwaukee, 1920s; mother, German-American Socialist and poet; Cortez' imprisonment during World War II as conscientious objector; role of IWW in Chicago Mexican-American community, 1940s; Cortez' role as artist and speaker for IWW, 1940s-1980s; anarchism and IWW.
- Malcolm Cowley, Jan 19, 1981 (Cassette 56, Box 1, Cd Cowley 1-2, Cd ohaloh020087p1 / ohaloh020087p2, Cd Access OH-02-91 / OH-02-092)
  Left in the Depression; League of Professional Groups, "Culture and the Crisis," 1932; the proletarian novel; John Reed Clubs; Popular Front; Spanish Civil War; reflections.
  Interview by Richard Wormser.
- Carl Cowl, Mar 13, 1983 (Box 1, Cassette 57, Cd ohaloh020198p1 / ohaloh020198p2, Cd Access OH-02-219, OH-02-220)
- Roy Curtis, Nov 4, 1984 (Cassette 308A-B)
  No access cassettes / Masters only
- Joseph Cvetas, Oct 22, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 58, Cd ohaloh020199p1 / ohaloh020199p2, Cd Cvetas 1, Cd Access OH-02-221)
  Family background in SNPJ (Slovenian Benefit Society); fraternal activities as child; fraternalism in 1980s.
- James Cannon, undated (Cassette n/a, Cd ohaloh020028p1 / ohaloh020028p2, Cd Access 29)
- Sam Darcy, 1981 (Box 1, Cassette 59 A-B, Cassette 59, Cd Darcy 1-3, Cd ohaloh020021b1p1 / ohaloh020021b1p2, Cd ohaloh020022b1p3, Cd Access OH-02-021 / OH-02-022 / OH-02-023)
  Immigrant background; Communist activities, 1920s; factionalism; Browderism; leaves CP; subsequent activities and reflections.
- Sam Darcy, Nov 3, 1994 (Cassette 342)
- Sam Darcy, Nov 4, 1994 (Cassette 343A-B)
- Saul Davidson, Mar 16, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020200p1 / ohaloh020200p2, Cassette 60, Box 1, Cd Davidson 1, Cd Access OH-02-222)
  "United Front" of various organizations for preservation of Yiddish language in Miami Beach; Davidson as former left activist become mainstream Yiddish activist; reflections on survival of Yiddish.
- Sam Davis, Nov 15, 1980 (Cd ohaloh020201b1p1 / ohaloh020201b1p2, Cd ohaloh020202b1p3, Cassette 61, Box 1, Cd Davis 1-2, Cd Access OH-02-223, OH-02-224, Cassette 61 A-B)
  Role of Jewish Left in New Haven, Conn. since 1920s; nature of Jewish community; split of socialists and Communists, 1920s; Yiddishe Kultur Farband choir and other activities; separation of Morgen Freiheit from Communists and cultural activities in YKUF/Jewish Currents circle.
- Zoltan Deak, Feb 17, 1983 (Box 1, Cassette 62, Cd Deak 1, Cd Access OH-02-024, Cd ohaloh020023p1 / ohaloh020023p2)
  Aesthetics of Hungarian-American radical press, Uj Elore and Hungarian Word, 1920s-present; immigration and interest in progressive press; circulation and internal structure of Uj Elore; shrinking of Hungarian-American milieu.
- Jeannette Dean, Apr 14, 1979 (Box 1, Cassette 63, Cd Dean 1)
  Background; union activities; radicalism & unions, UE in Newark.
- Solon De Leon Description: Socialist Party and reformism; Solon's break with Daniel DeLeon; IWW; Industrial Union League and Socialist Labor Party, c. 1900s-1930s., Dec 16, 1972 (Cassette 65A-C)
- Albina Delfino, Jan 8, 1981 (Cd Access OH-02-98 and OH-02-99, Cd ohaloh0200092b1p1 / ohaloh0200092b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200093b1p3 / ohaloh0200093b1p4, Box 1, Cassette 66 1-2, Cassette 66, Cd Delfino 1-2)
  Italian-American women and the Communist Party, Needle Trades Industrial Union, National Textile Workers Union; CP organizer in Lawrence, Providence, Boston, Corona, N.Y., 1930s-40s.
- Eugene Dennis Description: with introduction by Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, undated (Cassette 329)
  no access cassettes available / masters only
- Esther Dolgoff, Jan 27, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 67 A-B, Cassette 67, Cd OH-02-025 /OH-02-026, Cd ohaloh020024b1p1 / ohaloh020024b1p2, Cd ohaloh020025b1p3 / ohaloh020025b1p4, Cd Dolgoff 1-2)
  Anarchist women of the 1930s; character of anarchism.
- James Dolson, 1979 (Box 1, Cassette 64 A-E, Cd Dolson 1-5, Cassette 64A-E)
- Apr 3, 1983 (Cassette 68)
- Dora, Mar 25, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 69, Cd Dora 1)
  Student radicalism, 1930s; Communist Party; United Electrical Workers; social life and friends.
- Pauline Dougherty, Jan, 1982 (Cd 1, Box Dougherty 1-4, Cd ohaloh020203b1p1 / ohaloh020203b1p2 / ohaloh020204b1p3, Cd ohaloh020204b1p4 / ohaloh020205b1p5 /ohaloh020205b1p6, Cd ohaloh020206b1p7, Cassette 70, Cd Access OH-02-225, OH-02-226, OH-02-227, OH-02-228, Box 1, Cassette 70 A-D)
  Background in shoe town; college politics in depression; union activity in offices and the Left; McCarthy Era; reflections.
  Interview by Sy Singer.
- Susan Drake-Raphals, May 7, 1983 (Box 1, Cassette 71 A-B, Cd ohaloh020207b1p1 /ohaloh020207b1p2, Cd ohaloh020208b1p3 / ohaloh020208b1p4, Cassette 71, Cd Access OH-02-229)
  Workers Party, 1940s and her role in it; C.L.R. James in the 1940s.
- Hal Draper, Nov 5, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Draper 1-2, Cassette 72 A-B, Cd ohaloh020209b1p1 / ohaloh020209b1p2, Cd ohaloh020210b1p3 / ohaloh020210b1p4, Cassette 72, Cd Access OH-02-230, OH-02-231)
  Electronic transcript available
  Role as editor of Labor Action, 1949-1958; problems of "Shachtmanite" group and analysis offered in LA; developing writers and subjects for newspaper; political disintegration of group; Draper moves to Berkeley.
- Walter Duda, Mar 15, 1983 (Cassette 73, Cd ohaloh020211p1 / ohaloh020211p2, Box 1, Cd Access OH-02-232)
  Lithuanian-American Left activities around Connecticut's Brass Valley, 1920s-50s.
- Jane Dudley Description: Dance and left politics; New Dance group; Martha Graham; civil rights., 1981 (Cd Access OH-02-149, Cassette 74, Cd ohaloh0200139p1)
  Transcript available, Box 1 and Index available
- Raya Dunayevskaya Description: Trotskyism, 1930s; Johnson- Forest group, 1940s; coal strikes of 1949-50 and News and Letters organization., Mar 24, 1983 (Cassette 75)
- George Edwards Description: Garveyite, 1920s; semiprofessional football player, prohibition-era gangster, Kansas-Nebraska district, 1930s-40s., Nov 4, 1983 (Cassette 76A-C)
  Transcript availalbe, Box 1 and index available
- Herb Edwards Description: Wisconsin lumber, Industrial Workers of the World; Elmer Smith; San Quentin., Feb 12, 1972 (Item Transcript only)
- Hoddee Edwards Description: Boston Jewish community; Communist activist in California; People's World, 1949; life in Ghana; c. 1920s-60s., Nov 12, 1983 (Cassette 78A-B)
- Peter Elish, Jun 27, 1983 (Cassette 77)
- Melech Epstein Description: Editorship of Freiheit and Yiddish publications; Israel and 1970s American politics., Jan 9, 1974 (Cassette 79)
- Virginia Epstein, Mar 30, 1981 (Box 1, Cassette 80 A-B, Cassette 80, Cd Access OH-02-027 / OH-02-028, Cd V. Epstein 1-2, Cd ohaloh020026b1p1 / ohaloh020026b1p2, Cd ohaloh020027b1p3 / ohaloh020027b1p4)
  Born 1885; background in Dallas, Texas as child of mixed Episcopalian-Jewish marriage; in New York from 1908, Socialist Party, 1910s; Communist Party from 1920s; American Council on US-Soviet Friendship; Committee of American Women; local political activities in Queens, N.Y.
- Ernest Erber, Mar 23, 1984 (Cassette 365A-B)
- S. Evelyn Description: Young Communist League; anti-Nazi and pro-Republican Spain; 1930s., Jun 25, 1982 (Cassette no tape)
- Seymour Faber Description: Radical Zionism; Johnson-Forest Tendency; Detroit 1930s-60s., Mar 30, 1983 (Cassette 82A-B)
  Transcript available, Box 1 and index available
- Elmer Felhaber Description: Minnesota newspaper unionism; CIO and Communist Party; Ohio Left after WWII; c. 1930s-1950s., Feb 5, 1981 (Cassette 83A-B)
- Duncan Ferguson Description: (Memorial Meeting) Eulogy by Harry Ring, of sculptor and activist in Socialist Workers Party, 1940s-70s., 1975 (Cassette 84)
- Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Dec 1981 (Box 1, Cassette 85, Cd Ferlinghetti 1-2, Cd ohaloh020088p1 / ohaloh020088p2, Cd Access OH-02-093 / OH-02-094)
  Beat Generation in retrospect; San Francisco avant-garde arts and anarchism, 1940s and early 1950s; formation of City Lights book store and publishing company; artists in modern world.
- Joseph Figueredo, Nov 3, 1983 (Cassette 86, Cd ohaloh020212b1p1 / ohaloh020212b1p2 / ohaloh020213b1p3, Cd ohaloh020213b1p4 / ohaloh020214b1p5 / ohaloh020214b1p6, Cd ohaloh020215b1p7 / ohaloh020215b1p8, Box 1, Cd Figuerdo 1-4, Cassette 86 A-D, Cd Access OH-02-233, OH-02-234, OH-02-235, OH-02-236)
  Portuguese-American Left in New Bedford and Fall River, Mass., 1930s-40s; political origins in strikes of 1920s and Communist role; lack of formal fraternal and cultural structure and absence of regular Portuguese-language Communist press; use of local radio; Cold War pressures, 1940s, and departure to San Francisco; activities in ILWU, 1950s-present.
- Bruno Fisher, Nov 1982 (Cassette 308C)
- Morris Fisher, Mar 16, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Fisher 1, Cassette 87, Cd ohaloh020216p1 / ohaloh020216p2, Cd Access OH-02-237)
  Labor Zionism and Workmen's Circle; Jewish Socialist Farband, Miami Beach Yiddishkayt; c. 1930s-1970s.
- Jacob Fisherman, Nov 3, 1979 (Cassette 393)
- Henry Foner Description: Teacher's union activities; Communist Party and Ben Gold;, 1948-1970s., Mar 29, 1976 (Item Transcript only)
- Emmanuel Fried, 1977-1983 (Cassette 310A (May 1980) / 310B (Oct 30, 1980) / 310C (March 1980), Cassette 310D (June 8, 1977) / 310E June 1978))
- William (Bill) Friedland, May 6, 1983 (Box 1, Cassette 89, Cd ohaloh020217p1 / ohaloh020217p2, Cd Access OH-02-238)
  Cultural perspective in Workers Party; role of music in Friedland's life and creation of record, Songs for Sectarians; college teaching and sympathy for antiwar students, 1960s.
- Isadore Friedland & Max Fishgold, Mar 15, 1983 (Box 1, Cassette 90, Cd Friedland & Fishgold 1, Cd Access OH-02-239, Cd ohaloh020218p1 / ohaloh020218p2)
  Union activities and the Left, 1930s- 1950s.
- Mary Gale, Jan 29, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 91, Cd Access OH-02-240, OH-02-241, OH-02-242, Cd ohaloh020219b1p1 / ohaloh020219b1p2, Cd ohaloh020220b1p3 / ohaloh020220b1p4, Cd ohaloh020221b1p5 / ohaloh020221b1p6)
  Growing up in east New York and Queens in 1910s-20s; ILGWU, 1920s-30s; Scottsboro case, American Labor Party; family and home life in relation to her work and political activism.
- Alex & Faye Gardners; Abe Kantor; Hyman Hodes, Mar 15, 1983 (Box 1, Cassette 93 A-B, Cd Access OH-02-245, OH-02-246, Cassette 93, Cd ohaloh020224b1p1 / ohaloh020224b1p2, Cd ohaloh020225b1p3 / ohaloh020225b1p4)
  Jewish & Italian radicalism, 1930s-1950s; Unemployed councils; Workers' Club; WPA; Garibaldi Clubs; work with Marcantonio as his campaign manager, union activities.
- Sender Garlin, Oct 14, 1976 (Box 1, Cd Garlin 1-2, Cassette 92 A-B, Cd Access OH-02-243, OH-02-244, Cassette 92, Cd ohaloh020222b1p1 / ohaloh020222b1p2, Cd ohaloh020223b1p3 / ohaloh020223b1p4)
  Socialist Party; working at the Daily Worker, 1920s-30s.
- Hugo Gellert, Apr 4, 1984 (Cd Access Oh-02-030 / OH-02-031, Cd ohaloh020029b1p1 / ohaloh029b1p2, Cd ohaloh020030b1p3, Box 1, Cassette 94 A-B, Cassette 94, Cd Gellert 1-2)
- Sophie Melvin Gerson Description: Young Communist League; Passaic and Gastonia textile strikes; 1920s., Mar 26, 1976 (Item Transcript only)
- Joseph Giganti, Jul 26, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020226b1p1 / ohaloh020226b1p2, Cd ohaloh020227b1p3 / ohaloh020227b1p4, Cassette 96, Cd Access OH-02-247, OH-02-248, Box 1, Cassette 96 A-B)
  Italian-American Communist newspaper, II Lavoratore, editorial staff and theatrical commentary; nature of Italian-American Left milieu in Chicago, 1920s; expulsion from Communist movement; early Trotskyism; "Oehlerite" faction of Trotskyists, and their Chicago activity, 1930s; expulsion from Ohelerites and further political commitments.
- Todd Gitlin, Mar 1, 1970 (Box 1, Cd Gitlin 1, Cassette 97)
  Students for a Democratic Society, 1960s.
- Ann Ginger (Cd ohaloh020248b1p1 / ohaloh020248b1p2, Cd ohaloh020249b1p3 / ohaloh020249b1p4, Cd ohaloh020250b1p5 ohaloh020250b1p6, Cassette 124, Cd Access OH-02-271, OH-02-272, OH-02-273)
- Barbara Gittings, Jul 26, 1983 (Cassette 98A-C, Box 1, Cassette 98 A-C, Cd Gittings 1-4)
  Gay liberation movement, 1950s-70s.
  Interview by Howard August.
- Jessie Glaberma n Description: Socialist Workers Party and Workers Party in New York, Philadelphia and Detroit, 1930s-1950s., Aug 17, 1977 - Sep 3, 1977 (Cassette 99A-G)
- Martin Glaberman Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency; New York and Detroit, 1940s-50s., Mar 29, 1983 (Cassette 100)
- Ruth Glassman, Feb 1, 1979 (Cd ohaloh020228b1p1 / ohaloh020228b1p2, Cd ohaloh020229b1p3 / ohaloh020229b1p4, Cassette 101, Cd Access OH-02-249, OH-02-250, Box 1, Cd Glassman 1-2, Cassette 101 A-B)
  American Youth Congress, 1930s; WWII and shop agitation; women in factories, United Electrical Workers; struggles and problems.
- Katya Gilden, Nov 21, 1976 (Box 1, Cd Gilden 1-2, Cassette 309A, Cassette 95 A-B)
- Albert Glotzer, Dec 13, 1983; Dec 21, 1983; Mar 31, 1984 (Cd Access OH-02-251, OH-02-252, OH-02-253, OH-02-254, Cd ohaloh020230b1p1 / ohaloh020230b1p2 / ohaloh020231b1p3, Cd ohaloh020231b1p4 / ohaloh020232b1p5 / ohaloh020232b1p6, Cd ohaloh020233b1p7 / ohaloh020233b1p8, Cassette 102, Box 1, Cassette 102 A-D)
  Family background in Russia and Chicago; Communist Party, 1920s; American Trotskyism, late 1920s-30s; Workers Party, 1940s.
- Albert Glotzer, Oct 24, 1973 (Cassette 335A-B)
- Lillian Gold, Apr 4, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette 103 A-B, Cassette 103, Cd Access OH-02-032 / OH-02-033, Cd ohaloh020031b1p1 / ohaloh020031b1p2, Cd ohaloh020032b1p3 / ohaloh020032b1p4, Cd Gold 1-2)
  Grew up in NYC, earliest recollections of WWI, trying to find work and succeed in it, her involvement in the Socialist Party in 1933, work with War Resisters' League, FDR & trade union movement, union work with teachers in 1950.
- Itche Goldberg, Jun 5, 1982 (Box 1, Cd Goldberg (1982) 1, Cassette Access OH-02-034, Cassette 104, Cassette ohaloh020033)
  Immigration and Canadian Yiddish background; Left Yiddishkayt in New York, 1920s-30s; struggle for autonomy wihin Communist framework; Yiddish pedagogy versus politics; reflections.
- Itche Goldberg, Feb 17, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Goldberg (1983) 1, Cassette 105, Cd ohaloh020034p1 / ohaloh020034p2, Cd Access OH-02-035)
  Jewish cultural movement, and role of his humor in Jewish cultural life.
- K. Golden, Nov 21, 1976 (Cassette 366A-B)
- Mollie Goldstein, Nov 7, 1981 (Cd Access OH-02-036 / OH-02-037, Cassette 106, Box 1, Cd Goldstein 1-2, Cassette 106 A-B, Cd ohaloh020035b1p1 / ohaloh020035b1p2, Cd ohaloh020036b1p3)
  Communist Party; women's organizations; price and rent protests in Brooklyn and the Bronx; 1930s.
- Nina Goldstein, Mar 19, 1980 (Cd Access OH-02-255, OH-02-256, Cd ohaloh020234b1p1 /ohaloh020234b1p2, Cassette 107, Box 1, Cassette 107 A-B, Cd Goldstein 1-2)
  Early life in Russia, Canada; work and political life in Brownsville and East Flatbush, Brooklyn, 1920s-30s; Communist Party, Freihei t, International Workers Order; Russian War Relief and aid to Israel, 1940s; Jewish cultural movement, Miami Beach.
- Walter Goldwater Description: C.L.R. James; Workers Party; Trotskyism, anti-Stalinism, neo-conservatism, Pan-Africanism; 1930s-1960s., Feb 15, 1983 (Cassette 108A-B)
  no access cassette for 108B / master only
- Goolhman, undated (Cassette 394)
  no access cassette available / master only
- Helen Goodman, undated
- Michael Gordon Description: Frontier Films, Film and Photo League, 1930s., Mar 25, 1977 (Cassette 109)
- Grandma was an Activist, 1983 (Cassette 110A-C, Box 1, Cassette 110 A-C (note A at preservation), Cd Grandma was an Activist 2-3)
  Radio series on women radicals of 1930s, in six half-hour parts, produced from OHAL interviews for WBAI-FM; includes excerpts from interviews with Louise Thompson, Jane Dudley, Alice Dodge Wolfson, Meridel LeSueur et. al.
- Leah-Dillon Grant Description: Yiddish literary milieu; Johnson-Forest Tendency; c. 1920s-1940., Jul 24, 1983 (Cassette 111)
- Samuel Greenberg Description: Yiddish culture and the Left; Los Angeles Yiddish Left from the 1930s-present., Oct 27, 1982 (Cassette 112A-B)
- Sam Grober, Nov 5, 1979 (Cassette 395)
- Sarah Gudelman, Nov 3, 1979 (Cassette 396A-B)
- National Guardian Forum Description: New Communist Party; criticism of 1960s' politics., May 26, 1973 (Cassette 113)
- Oive Halonen, Feb 27, 1978 (Cassette 114, Box 1, Cd Halonen 1-2)
  Finnish-American radicalism, Minnesota and Oregon, 1910s-30s; participation in Spanish Civil War as member of Abraham Lincoln Brigade; experiences as Seattle machinist, 1940s-60s.
- Michael Hanusiak Description: Ukrainian-American Left; International Workers Order; effect of McCarthyism; 1930s-1940s., Mar 30, 1983 (Cassette 115)
- Louis Harap, Mar 19, 1978 (Cassette 116A-B, Box 1, Cd Harap 1-2, Cassette 116 A-B)
  Harvard University, 1930s; Jewish Survey, 1940s; Jewish Life, 1940s-50s; Rosenberg case; Jewish Currents 1950s-70s.
  Transcript and index available
- Harlem Riots Inquiry, Mar 14, 1965 (Cassette 386)
- Michael Harrington, Oct 6, 1969 (Cd Access OH-02-257, OH-02-258, Cd ohaloh020236p1 /ohaloh020236p2, Cassette 117, Box 1, Cd Harrington 1-2)
  "Prehistory" of Students for a Democratic Society, late 1950s; SDS, 1960s.
- Michael Harrington, May 2, 1988 (Cd Access OH-02-259, OH-02-260, OH-02-261, Cassette 117.5, Cd ohaloh020237b1p1 / ohaloh020237b1p2, Cd ohaloh020238b1p3 / ohaloh020238b1p4, Cd ohaloh020239b1p5 / ohaloh020239b1p6, Box 1, Cd Harrington 3-5, Cassette 117.5 A-C)
- Daniel Hartquist, Feb 5, 1981 (Cassette 118, Box 1, Cd Hartquist 1-2, Cassette 118 A-B, Cd ohaloh020240b1p1 / ohaloh020240b1p2, Cd ohaloh020241b1p3 /ohaloh020241b1p4, Cd Access OH-02-262, OH-02-263, OH-02-264)
  Socialist movement in Sweden and Swedish-American Socialism; Left in New England, 1930s-40s; reflections on American Communism.